欢迎您采访前端工程师。
Welcome to interviewing for
front end engineers.
我选择了漫画漫画，因为这通常是采访的内容。
I chose Comic Sans because that's
what interviews often are.
他们太傻了他们是任意的
They're kind of silly, they're arbitrary.
没有一套你去接受采访的标准或规则和惯例
There's no set of standards or rules and
practices that you walk to an interview,
你说我知道接下来会发生什么
you say I know exactly
what is gonna happen,
或者我知道他们要问的问题的类型
or I know exactly the type of
questions they're gonna ask.
不是随机的
No, it's random.
有多少乒乓球能装在校车上 ?
How many ping pong balls
can fit on a school bus?
是啊我们都被问到这样的奇怪问题了
Yeah, we've all been asked
weird questions like that.
有些人在外面冻伤了一分钟
Some of you out there froze up for
a minute.
你就像，十个乒乓球，不，有二十个人。
You're like, ten ping pong,
no, there's 20 people.
这不是真正的问题
Not a real question.
别担心我不会问这类的问题的
Don't worry, I'm not gonna ask any of
those sort of kinda trivia questions.
我真正想的是解决这个问题
What I really wanna get to is solving this
problem of arbitrary questions during
前端面试。
front end interviewing.
或者走进采访不知道会发生什么
Or walking into an interview and
not knowing what's gonna happen,
这些步骤是什么
what the steps are.
特别是那些从未访问过的人
Especially people who have never
interviewed, particularly for
一个前端的角色你不知道该期望什么
a front end role,
you don't know what to expect.
我们今天要把所有这些都包括在内
We're gonna cover all of that today.
但是我想建立的是一个关于前面谈应该如何进行的
But really, what I wanna set up is a
rubric of how front end interviews should
你应该问的问题的类型
go, the type of questions
you should be asking.
听起来不错吧
Sound good?
好，我叫杰姆 - 扬，我是高级软件工程师。
All right, my name is Jem Young,
I am a senior software engineer.
让我们看看我的超级英雄出身
Let's see,
my superhero origin story would be
好奇心是我作为一个工程师出生的方式。
curiosity was how I was
born as an engineer.
星图是我孵化的地方
Startups were where I was incubated.
过去四年里的 Netflix 是我的锻压
Netflix for the past four years,
been my forge.
但教书是我的石
But teaching is my whetstone.
让我锐利 库兹你在一份工作上花的时间太长了
Keeps me sharp.
Cuz you spend too long at one job,
你总是很擅长一件事
you tend to get really good at one thing.
所以我喜欢出去教书，尽量帮别人。
So I like to go out and teach and
try to help others as best I can.
而且几乎我教过的每一个课程
And also,
almost every course I've ever taught,
我也从你们那里学到了些东西
I learned something from you all too.
但真的，我为什么要教这个课程，我就可以去做了。
But really, why I wanna teach this
course is so I can go on rants.
我喜欢 rants，我在播客的播客节目中有很多 rants 。
I love rants, I got on a lot of rants on
the podcast I'm on, Front End Happy Hour.
当我们喝饮料的时候，我们谈论的是前端的东西，而且非常好。
Where we have drinks, we talk about
front end things, and it's pretty good.
但是，这只是一个平台，让我了解事情的发展。
But again, it's just a platform for
me going on rants about things.
我真正想去采访的是采访，因为我有
And what I really wanna go on rants
on is interviewing, because I have so
很多很好的面试 rants
many good interview rants.
别担心这就来了
Don't worry, that's coming.
会很精彩的
It's gonna be very exciting.
所以我想问大家的第一项问题是你没大声说出来
So the first question I wanna ask
everybody, and you don't say it out loud,
想想，为什么采访这么困难?
just think,
why is interviewing so difficult?
怎么了
Yes?
> > 大部分都适合双方。
&gt;&gt; It's mostly about fit for both parties.
因此，即使你有能力，也未必是一个好的配合。
So even if you have the skills,
it might not be a good fit.
> > 嗯，那是真的。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, that's true.
但让我们再做点更广泛的工作。
Let's go a little broader, though.
有点大
Little broader.
>> 你真的不知道应该会有什么样的问题。
&gt;&gt; You don't really know what to expect
what type of questions are gonna be there.
看来每个公司都有自己的标准
And it seems like every company
has their own standards,
所以你不知道该怎么做
so you don't really know
how to prepare for it.
> > 嗯我喜欢那个
&gt;&gt; Yeah, I like that one.
我认为这更准确地说明了为什么采访的难度如此之大。
I think that's a bit more accurate on
why interviewing is just so difficult.
因为我们对工程的概念都有不同的想法。
Because we all have this different
idea about what engineering is.
因此，我们对工程应该是什么样的想法都有不同的想法。
Thus, we all these different idea
about what engineering should be.
老实说，我们都是工程师的一种不诚实的观点。
And we all have, honestly, kind of a
dishonest view of ourselves as engineers.
我们有这样的想法，就是我们如何构建事物，以及如何解决问题。
We have this idea of how we build
things and how we solve problems.
我们尝试向其他人申请这个卢布，但我们都不一样。
And we try to apply that rubric to
everybody else, but we're all different.
这让我们都很美丽，我们都有点不同。
That's what makes us all beautiful
is we're all a little bit different.
这就是为什么你不能真正走进去说有几个 SAT 面试
And that's why you can't really just walk
in and say there's the SATs of interviews,
或者类似的东西
or something like that.
因为我们都有一点点细微的细微差别
Because we all have just a little bit
of nuances that make us a little bit
不一样
different.
但最后我想知道为什么采访是如此的
But at the end of the day,
I like to think why interviewing is so
因为我们都不一样
difficult is because we're
all a little different and
因为我们对工程的看法有不同的看法
because we all think a little
differently about what engineering is.
这就使它具有挑战性。
That makes it challenging.
所以再把这个打破一点，我那天看了这个伟大的博客，
So to break that down a little bit more,
I read this great blog post the other day,
我鼓励你在某个时候读
and I encourage you to
read it at some point.
但这个人把它砸坏了
But this person, they broke it down and
他们说基本上有三种不同类型的工程师。
they said there is essentially
three different types of engineers.
有工程师说工程只是数学。
There are the engineers who
say engineering is just math.
所有关于算法都是关于效率的
It's all about the algorithm,
it's all about efficiency,
都是关于聪明的密码和操纵号码的
it's all about clever code and
manipulating numbers around.
在这一天的最后，我们正在做的是，我们正在翻转开关，
Cuz at the end of the day, that's what
we're doing, we're flipping switches,
0 和 1 。
ones and zeros.
这就是工程的全部，算法，它的美丽。
And that's what engineering is all about,
the algorithms, the beauty of it all.
是啊，而且很多时候，这就是为什么我们在访谈中有很多算法问题。
Yeah, and often, that's why we get a lot
of algorithm questions in interviews.
有人想说这个人像数学家吗 ?
People are trying to say does this
person think like a mathematician?
这个人认为算法吗 ?
Does this person think in algorithms?
他们看着一个问题说 " 双排 "
Do they look at a problem and
say Double sort,
嗯，那是一个很好的现在申请的算法。
yes, that is a great
algorithm to apply right now.
另一类程序员是编程，是关于硬件性能的。
Another type of programmer is programming
is all about hardware performance.
这都是关于低级别的比特流，接近金属的程度，你能理解吗 ?
It's all about that low level bit-lipping,
how close to the metal, do you understand?
有人认识这样的人吗 ?
Anybody know anybody like that,
the hardware people?
他们是不同的人
They're a different bunch.
他们也很棒 有这种类型的人
They're good, too.
There's those type of people.
他们是黑客和工匠
They're the hackers, the tinkerers.
可能是在集会上写的
Probably writing in assembly.
您是否了解 CP 注册是什么 ?
Trying to understand do you
understand what a CP register is?
了解 L1 高速缓存与二级高速缓存的对比吗 ?
Do you understand what the L1
cache is versus the L2 cache?
性能问题。
Performance questions.
那个低级的基本知识
That low-level base knowledge.
你会得到这样的面试问题，那是非常低级的事情。
You get interview questions like that,
that really low level stuff.
还有第三类工程师，工兵，建筑工人，
And then, there's the third category of
engineers, the tinkerers, the builders,
但是你想描述的是大多数人坐的地方
however you wanna describe them,
that's where most people sit.
在我们理想的世界里，我们就像，我都是关于表演的。
In our ideal world, we're like,
I'm all about performance.
或者我是一个数学的人，这就是我所做的。
Or I'm a math person, that's all I do.
但如果你是一个前端工程师，一般来说，你是在建造东西。
But if you're a front end engineer,
generally, you're building things.
这就是与人交谈的问题
That's about talking to people,
了解规范，了解不同的浏览器兼容性。
understanding specs, understanding
different browser compatibilities.
所有这些边缘病例
All these edge cases,
所有我们不认为是工程的事情比如会议
all the things that we don't think
of as engineering, like meetings or
有效地传达了你的想法那就是第三类人
efficiently communicating your ideas,
that's the third category of people.
这就是我们大多数人撒谎的地方。
And that's where most of us lie.
但大多数采访都不是这样的。
But most interviews
aren't like that at all.
你不接受采访的人说
There's no interview
where you walk in you say
嘿有个座位这个是我们的设计师
hey, have a seat, this is our designer.
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you.
这是我们的产品经理。
This is our product manager.
我们今天要去做一个产品
And we're gonna walk through
building a product today.
所以我们要把它规范出来
So we're gonna spec it out.
你和其他工程师碰面了
Gonna have you meet other engineers, and
我们会让你在一天结束前建造一个产品
we're gonna have you build
a product by the end of the day.
这将更接近我们在现实生活中所做的事情。
That would be closer to what
we do in the real life.
但这并不是发生的事情。
But that's not what happens at all.
所以很多与采访的脱节来自于
So a lot of the disconnect with
interviewing comes from this idea of
我们不知道我们是什么样的工程师
we don't know what type
of engineers we are.
我们不知道我们想要雇用的工程师的类型。
And we don't know what type
of engineers we wanna hire.
这只是我的意见。
This is just my opinion.
采访有很多问题，
There are many problems with interviewing,
但我觉得很多是我们不了解自己的
but I think a lot of it comes from
we don't understand ourselves.
我们不明白什么是工程。
We don't understand what engineering is.